nethouseprices.com 2018-12-14

# Privacy | Nethouseprices.com

## Privacy Policy

**Introduction**

Nethouseprices Limited ( **“Nethouseprices”, “our”, “we”** ) takes your right to privacy very seriously; the following Privacy and Cookie policy ( **“Privacy Policy”** ), aims to give you information on how Nethouseprices collects and processes your personal data when you use nethouseprices.com ( **“Website”** ). 

The Website is not intended for children (those aged 13 and under) and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

It is important that you read this Privacy Policy together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This Privacy Policy supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

The data protection law in the UK will change on 25 May 2018. Although this Privacy Policy sets out most of your rights under the new laws, we may not yet be able to respond to some of your requests (for example, a request for the transfer of your personal data) until May 2018 as we are still working towards getting our systems ready for some of these changes. When you register or use the Website you will be asked to "opt in" to our Privacy Policy i.e. to confirm that you agree to our use of any personal data that we may collect from you as a user of the Website as set out in this Privacy Policy. If you do not give your consent, you will not be able to use the Website as we will be unable to provide our services and facilities to you. You can withdraw your consent to our use of your personal data at any time by cancelling your membership (see Your Rights).

For ease of reading, we have divided this Privacy Policy into several sections:

  * What information do we collect?
  * How and why do we use/share your information?
  * How long do we keep your information for?
  * Cookies
  * Your Rights

**What information do we collect?**

What is personal data?

Where this Privacy Policy refers to ‘personal data’ it is referring to data about you (or other living people) from which you could be identified – such as your name, your date of birth, your contact details and even your IP address.

By law all organisations in the UK are obliged to process your personal data in certain ways and to ensure that you are given an appropriate amount of information about how they use it. You also have various rights to seek information from those organisations about how they are using your data, and to prevent them from processing it unlawfully. For more information about these rights, please see the ‘Your Rights’ section of this Privacy Policy.

Data we collect from you

Depending on how you interact with us, Nethouseprices will collect you:

  * Name
  * IP Address
  * Contact details: E-mail address, postal address, telephone number; and mobile number

We collect this data in a number of ways, these include:

  * When you register to use the Website
  * When you submit a form to participate in any promotions and competitions offered by us
  * When you use our online property valuation tool
  * When you visit our Website through cookies

Updating your information

If you want to update the information you have previously given to us (e.g. if you have recently moved house or changed your email address), you can contact Nethouseprices at: [info@nethouseprices.com](mailto:info@nethouseprices.com) or change it in your ‘My Nethouseprices’ account.

Collecting your information

Where we collect your personal data we may use that information to:

  * Operate the service and send you information you request on the Website
  * Generate aggregate statistics about our Website visitors and users of the service
  * Collect broad demographic information for aggregate use
  * Improve the content of our web pages
  * Administer this Website
  * Customise the service we provide to you
  * Notify you when your registration with the service is due to expire
  * Handle enquiries, orders or applications submitted to us by you
  * Verify your identity (for example, in the event you participate in a promotion or are a competition winner)
  * Conduct surveys and market research
  * Send you our newsletter and information about products and services that may interest you, if you have agreed to us doing so. This may be by email. If at any time you do not wish to continue to receive these details then contact us using these details: [info@nethouseprices.com](mailto:info@nethouseprices.com)
  * Serve you with the advertisements that you see on the Website and other external websites.

Why is Nethouseprices allowed to use your information in this way?

Nethouseprices will only use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us at [info@nethouseprices.com](mailto:info@nethouseprices.com) or changing the settings in your ‘My Nethouseprices’ account.

Sharing your information

Depending on how and why you provide us with your personal data. We may share it in the following ways:

  * We may analyse and disclose aggregate statistics about our Website visitors and users of our service in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers and other reputable third parties and for other lawful purposes, but these statistics will include no personally identifying information.
  * We may disclose personal data if required to do so by law or if we believe that such action is necessary to protect and defend the rights, property or personal safety of the Website or its visitors.
  * We may share data which you submit or generate in the course of using the online valuation tool with our partners and with other users of our website more generally, if we have first obtained your prior consent to do so.
  * If we have first obtained your consent to do so, Nethouseprices may share your information with our trusted partners so that they can provide information to you about products and services that may interest you. This may be by email, telephone or direct mail. If at any time you do not wish us to share your information in this way, then you can opt out any time by contacting Nethouseprices at [info@nethouseprices.com](mailto:info@nethouseprices.com) or changing the settings in your ‘My Nethouseprices’ account.

Service Providers

We will use third party service providers to undertake processing operations on our behalf, and this may require us to share your personal data with them. These service providers provide us with a variety of administrative, statistical, and technical services. We will only provide service providers with the minimum amount of personal data they need to fulfil the services we request, and we stipulate that they protect this information and do not use it for any other purpose. We take these relationships seriously and oblige all of our data processors to sign contracts with us that clearly set out their commitment to respecting individual rights, and their commitments to assisting us to help you exercise your rights as a data subject.

For example, if you use a credit or debit card to make a payment to us, we will send your details to [PayPal], who we employ to do our online payment processing. Nethouseprices will not keep your card details, other than the type of card used. However, details may be stored by our payment providers (i.e. PayPal) for the purposes of processing further payments you have instructed us to collect.

Please note that some of our service providers are based outside of the European Economic Area (the **“EEA”** ). Where we transfer your data to a service provider that is outside of the EEA we seek to ensure that appropriate safeguards are in place to make sure that your personal data is held securely and that your rights as a data subject are upheld – in almost all cases we do this by ensuring that the agreements between us and our chosen service providers contain what are called the ‘model clauses’ that oblige them to treat your personal data as if they themselves were based in the EEA.

Links to third party sites

Please note that where we provide links to third party websites that are not affiliated with Nethouseprices such sites are out of our control and are not covered by this Privacy Policy, regardless of whether they use our branding or logo on their websites. If you access third party sites using the links provided, the operators of these sites may collect information from you that could be used by them, in accordance with their own privacy policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

**How long do we keep your information for?**

Data retention

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirement.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see ‘Your Rights’ below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

Data storage and security

Nethouseprices takes the protection of your information very seriously. We use encryption (SSL) to protect your personal data when appropriate, and all the information provided to Nethouse prices is stored securely once we receive it.

Nethouseprices may store your personal data on secure servers either on our premises or in secure third party data centres

**Cookies**

A cookie is a text-only string of information that a website transfers to the cookie file of the browser on your computer's hard disk so that the website can remember who you are.

A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the 'lifetime' of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number.

Two types of cookies are used on this Website:

**session cookies**  \- temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser until you leave The Website.

**persistent cookies**  \- these remain in the cookie file of your browser for much longer (though how long will depend on the lifetime of the specific cookie).

Cookies can help a website to arrange content to match your preferred interests more quickly. Most major websites use cookies. Cookies cannot be used by themselves to identify you.

Find out more about [cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/) by contacting us at info@nethouseprices.com or visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

How we use cookies on our Website and what information we collect

Session cookies

  * To allow you to carry information across pages of our site and avoid having to sign in many times.
  * Within registration to allow you to access stored information.

Persistent cookies:

  * To help us recognise you as a unique visitor (a number) when you return to the Website and to allow us to tailor content or advertisements to match your preferred interests or to avoid showing you the same adverts repeatedly.
  * To compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use the Website and to help us improve the structure of the Website. We cannot identify you personally in this way.
  * Within research surveys to ensure you are not invited to complete a questionnaire too often or after you have already done so.
  * To store registration information so that you only have to re-enter your password each time you visit the Website

Please note that we use Google Analytics to collect information about you in aggregate form to help Nethouseprices understand how the Website is being use and to help Nethouseprices customise the Website for you. For more information about Google’s privacy policy, please visit <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/>. If you do not wish to allow the use of Google Analytics cookies at all, Google provides an opt-out plug-in for most common website browsers <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

Third party cookies

Third parties serve cookies are used on the Website for the following purposes:

  * To serve advertisements on our site and track whether these advertisements are clicked on by users.
  * To control how often you are shown a particular advertisement.
  * To tailor content to your preferences.
  * To count the number of anonymous users of our site.

Disabling or enabling cookies

  * You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, you may not be able to use all the interactive features of our Website if cookies are disabled.

What can I do to manage cookies stored on my computer?

By using the Website you consent to our data collection, storing, accessing, sharing and usage of cookies or other information on your device that takes place on the Website, app, email publication or other property as a consequence of your use of the Website.

There are a number of ways to manage cookies. If you use different computers in different locations you will need to ensure that each browser is adjusted to suit your cookie preferences.

Some modern browsers have a feature that will analyse website privacy policies and allow a user to control their privacy needs. These are known as 'P3P' features (Privacy Preferences Platform Find further information on [P3P](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/p3p-cookies/index.html).

You can easily delete any cookies that have been installed in the cookie folder of your browser. For example, if you are using Microsoft Windows Explorer:

  * Open 'Windows Explorer'
  * Click on the 'Search' button on the tool bar
  * Type 'cookie' into the search box for 'Folders and Files'
  * Select 'My Computer' in the 'Look In' box
  * Click 'Search Now'
  * Double click on the folders that are found
  * 'Select' any cookie file
  * Hit the 'Delete' button on your keyboard

If you are not using Microsoft Windows Explorer, then you should select 'cookies' in the 'Help' function for information on where to find your cookie folder.

What can I do to stop cookies being installed on my browser?

All web browsers enable you to set your cookie preferences before you start surfing.

Netscape Navigator 3.0  
Netscape 4.0+  
Netscape 6.0+  
Firefox 2.0+ / 3.0+ / 4.0+/8.0+  
Internet Explorer 3.0  
Internet Explorer 4.0  
Internet Explorer 5.0+  
Internet Explorer (IE) 7.0+  
Internet Explorer (IE) 8.0+  
Internet Explorer (IE) 9.0+  
Internet Explorer (IE) 11.0+  
Google Chrome  
Safari  
Opera 

I like to control which cookies are being set on my browser, but the alerts are rather annoying - is there any way that I can stop them?

The called P3P (Privacy Preferences Platform) to match your preferences with the privacy policy of a website. For more information about this, please click below.

Set preferences on [Internet Explorer 7+](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/internet-explorer7-plus.html)  
Set preferences on [Netscape 7](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/pref-netscape7.html)

**Your Rights**

As a data subject you have a number of rights in relation to your personal data. Below, we have described the various rights that you have, as well as how you can exercise them.

**Right of Access**

You may, at any time, request access to the personal data that we hold which relates to you (you may have heard of this right being described as a "subject access request").

Please note that this right entitles you to receive a copy of the personal data that we hold about you in order to enable you to check that it is correct and to ensure that we are processing that personal data lawfully. It is not a right that allows you to request personal data about other people, or a right to request specific documents from us that do not relate to your personal data.

You can exercise this right at any time by writing to us on [info@nethouseprices.com](mailto:info@nethouseprices.com) or by using the contact form set out here and telling us that you are making a subject access request. You do not have to fill in a specific form to make this kind of request.

**Your Right to Rectification and Erasure**

You may, at any time, request that we correct personal data that we hold about you which you believe is incorrect or inaccurate. You may also ask us to erase personal data if you do not believe that we need to continue retaining it (you may have heard of this right described as the “right to be forgotten”).

Please note that we may ask you to verify any new data that you provide to us and may take our own steps to check that the new data you have supplied us with is right. Further, we are not always obliged to erase personal data when asked to do so; if for any reason we believe that we have a good legal reason to continue processing personal data that you ask us to erase we will tell you what that reason is at the time we respond to your request.

You can exercise this right at any time by writing to us using the contact details set out here and telling us that you are making a request to have your personal data rectified or erased and on what basis you are making that request. If you want us to replace inaccurate data with new data, you should tell us what that new data is. You do not have to fill in a specific form to make this kind of request.

Your Right to Restrict Processing

Where we process your personal data on the basis of a legitimate interest (see the section of this Privacy Policy which explains why we use your personal data) you are entitled to ask us to stop processing it in that way if you feel that our continuing to do so impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms or if you feel that those legitimate interests are not valid.

You may also ask us to stop processing your personal data (a) if you dispute the accuracy of that personal data and want us verify that data's accuracy; (b) where it has been established that our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where we no longer need to process your personal data (and would otherwise dispose of it) but you wish for us to continue storing it in order to enable you to establish, exercise or defend legal claims.

Please note that if for any reason we believe that we have a good legal reason to continue processing personal data that you ask us to stop processing, we will tell you what that reason is, either at the time we first respond to your request or after we have had the opportunity to consider and investigate it.

You can exercise this right at any time by writing to us using the contact details set out here and telling us that you are making a request to have us stop processing the relevant aspect of your personal data and describing which of the above conditions you believe is relevant to that request. You do not have to fill in a specific form to make this kind of request.

Your Right to Portability

Where you wish to transfer certain personal data that we hold about you, which is processed by automated means, to a third party you may write to us and ask us to provide it to you in a commonly used machine-readable format.

Because of the kind of work that we do and the systems that we use, we do not envisage this right being particularly relevant to the majority of individuals with whom we interact. However, if you wish to transfer your data from us to a third party we are happy to consider such requests.

Your Right to stop receiving communications

For details on your rights to ask us to stop sending you various kinds of communications, please contact us.

Your Right to object to automated decision making and profiling

**You have the right to** be informed about the existence of any automated decision making and profiling of your personal data, and where appropriate, be provided with meaningful information about the logic involved, as well as the significance and the envisaged consequences of such processing that affects you.

**Exercising your rights**

When you write to us making a request to exercise your rights we are entitled to ask you to prove that you are who you say you are. We may ask you to provide copies of relevant ID documents to help us to verify your identity.

It will help us to process your request if you clearly state which right you wish to exercise and, where relevant, why it is that you are exercising it. The clearer and more specific you can be the faster and more efficiently we can deal with your request. If you do not provide us with sufficient information then we may delay actioning your request until you have provided us with additional information (and where this is the case we will tell you).

For our contact details, please see here.
